PROFESSOR: So what tree
search should I use?
So here's my suggested answer.
What should you do?
You should use Expectimax.
Expectimax is the more general
search procedure.
You should basically always, in
principle, use Expectimax.
But how do we use Expectimax?
Well, here's the Expectimax tree.
I take an action in the tree, then my
opponent does their opponent thing,
and then I take an action again.
All of the value in Expectimax,
in this case, is knowing what
probabilities to associate
with the outcomes.
And so when I get to the node that
represents my opponent, and I need to
decide how likely they are to do various
things, I need to figure out
the probabilities.
And the way I do that is I set up a
little side computation where I'd
simulate the opponent--
they do their thing--
and I figure out what the
opponent is going to do.
The opponent is going to go to the right
if it uses the minimax action
according to its tree.
So with some probability,
it's going to do that.
With some probability, it's
going to move at random.
And that lets me compute these values.
So that's cool.
Expectimax is the general case.
In this case, it's kind of bad news
computationally, because every single
chance node triggers a minimax
computation that
simulates your opponent.
You say, that's not too bad.
My opponent's only going to depth 2.
All right.
Well, what if your opponent had some
model of you, and you knew that?
Well, now when you do your opponent's
tree, inside your opponent's tree, you
need to simulate your opponent
simulating you.
This gets unmanageable very, very
quickly, except for one case, which is
minimax, where this thought process
of your opponent simulating you
stimulating it stimulating you
is just the game tree itself.
So in the minimax case, this all folds
down nicely, and you only have one
game tree to worry about.
And for this reason, it's very often the
case that if you go too far down
this embedded belief process, eventually
you'll just want to use
minimax for computational reasons.
But in this particular case that we've
set up, Expectimax lets us do the
right thing.